This is the PC run in CentOS 6.8, open the command prompt and go to the linux driver
files which is downloaded from the link provided at the beginning of the video.
Untar the driver and go to the driver directory Login as adminstrator.
Install the driver
Launch the driver
In this GUI, user is able to disable or enable read & write transfer, changing transfer size
in dword and number of descriptors.
The number of dword is limited to 2048 which is 8kB DMA transfer size to cater all different
PCIe configuration even through the example today PCIe gen3x8 design is able to run up
to 64kB DMA transfer size.
Besides that, the descriptor controller supports up to 128 descriptors for read and write DMAs.
Now we start to run the DMA transfer, type 1 to run both read and write simultaneous.
The result show pass and the speed is around 5.9GBps in both read and write transfer.
Changing the DMA transfer size to 2048 dword which is 8kB, and run the dma in infinate
loop. the throughput increasing to 6.4Gbps due to bigger transfer size.
This is end of the demo for PCIe AVMM DMA reference design in Linux Machine.
Next, I will run the second demo in Windows machine.
Similar to First Demo , I will program the FPGA on the development kits and continue
with power on the desktop PC with Windows 7.
Open the windows driver downloaded previously and install the driver by following the instruction
files inside the driver directory.
This machine has the driver pre-installed and I’m going to launch the Windows GUI
for AVMM DMA by open up the execution file.
Click on DMA.
The message below shows a gen3x8 device is detected.
Go to setup tab, you can change the DMA default setting in this tab such as disable DMA read
or write transfer, changing the number of iteration or data pattern.
By default, this application will run both read and write DMA for 100 iteration by using
random data.
Go to debug tab, we can set the DMA descriptor address and read write the data in FPGA memory.
In order to run the DMA successfully, the DMA descriptor address must be set exactly
as the based address which is set in PCIe AVMM DMA IP core inside the qsys design file.
Error tab is not ready at this moment but it will be ready in future release version.
Back to the main tab and run the DMA transfer by clicking start button.
Total 100 iteraction has been completed with average of 6.0GB/s and 6.1GB/s for both read
and write transfer.
You have successfully execute the Windows driver to perform the DMA transfer.
Thanks you for watching this video