HI, Greeting to you.
I’m Kee Chiew from Intel PSG IP Application Team.
Today, I would like to show how to run PCIe AVMM DMA reference design in Arria 10 device.
At the end of this video, you will be able to execute the provided Linux driver and Windows
driver to perform DMA transfer.
In this video, I will run the design in two different operating system which is CentOS
6.8 in first demo and Windows 7 in second demo.
I’m using Quartus Prime software version 16.0.2 and Arria 10 GX FPGA Development kit
as example.
Notes that, similar method is applicable to all V-series devices including Arria V, Cyclone
V and Stratix V.
This is the link to download the reference design and also the driver for DMA application.
Firstly, download the PCIe A10 AVMM DMA reference design.
I will use the gen3x8 design inside the zip files to facilitate the demo.
For Linux user, please download the linux driver to your Linux machine.
Similar to Windows user, here is the link to download the 64-bit Windows driver.
Open the archive design by using Quartus, open up the qsys design file.
This design consist of PCIe AVMM DMA IP core, on chip memory and clock.
Please take notes that transceiver PLL and DMA descriptor controller is generated inside
the PCI AVMM DMA IP core.
The drivers will access to DMA descriptor controller through these base address.
The On chip memory, memory size is set more than 64kB in order to support the maximum
capability of DMA controller in the IP core (which is 64kB of transfer size) for 256-bit
interface.
Currently, the maximum DMA transfer size for 128-bits is only 8kB.
However, it will increase in the future version of the Quartus Prime software.
This is the design that I’m going to demo in Linux and Windows machine.
This is the hardware setup for Arria 10 AVMM DMA reference design.
On the left is a desktop PC for reference design demo, and on the right is a laptop
with Quartus II software installed.
The Arria 10 PCIe development kit is slot into PCIe slot in the motherboard.
Please make sure your PCIe slot in the motherboard is able to support up to gen3x8.
In order to get FPGA ready before the PC enumeration happened, we need to power up the development
kit and program the by using the laptop before the desktop PC is power on.
Let’s start to program the FPGA now.
After that, power on the desktop PC.